What are you capable of?
Chronicle is a science fiction, drama, thriller film directed by Josh Trank.
Three high school students make an incredible discovery, leading to
their developing uncanny powers beyond their understanding.
As they learn to control their abilities and use them to their advantage, their lives
start to spin out of control, and their darker sides begin to take over.
Andrew Detmer, played by Dane DeHaan.
Matt Garetty, played by Alex Russell.
Steve Montgomery, played by Michael B. Jordan.
Richard Detmer, played by Michael Kelly.
Casey Letter, played by Ashley Hinshaw.
Karen Detmer, played by Bo Petersen.
Chronicle is a 2012 American found footage film directed by Josh Trank in his
feature-length directorial debut, and written by Max Landis.
It follows three Seattle high school seniors—bullied Andrew (Dane DeHaan), his
cousin Matt (Alex Russell), and the popular Steve (Michael B.
Jordan)—who form a bond after gaining telekinetic powers from an unknown object and
using them for fun, until Andrew begins going down a darker path.
Chronicle premiered at the Gérardmer Film Festival on January 28, 2012, and was
released in the United States on February 3, by 20th Century Fox.
The film grossed $127 million against a budget of $15 million.
It received generally positive reviews, and received a nomination for
Best Science Fiction Film at the 39th Saturn Awards.
The film explores themes of friendship, flying, seattle,
washington, telekinesis, coming of age.
The tone is emotional and dark and thought_provoking.